# **Terrence Ryan**

Developer Advocate for Google Cloud Platform

# Summary

I love technology that helps people extract ideas from their heads and into something real - be it code, design, or hardware. I enjoy working in a role that that allows me use my people skills, broad range of experiences, and technical knowledge to inspire people make their ideas concrete.

# Experience

## **Developer Advocate at Google**

December 2014 - Present

## **Developer Evangelist Manager at Adobe Systems**

November 2012 - October 2014 (1 year 11 months)

Manage a team of Creative Cloud evangelists focused on Creative Cloud in the Enterprise.

## **Developer Evangelist at Adobe**

February 2009 - November 2012 (3 years 9 months)

My role is to encourage developers to use tools and technologies that Adobe has to offer or support. It involves taking publicly to developer communities, working on Open Source projects, and offering advice online.

#### I.T. Director at The Wharton School

August 2008 - January 2009 (5 months)

Hired to modernize code base and publishing system for Knowledge@Wharton, an online journal, targeting audiences in the English, Spanish, Portuguese, and Chinese speaking world.

#### Responsibilities included:

- · Upgrading custom coded journal site with millions of readers
- · Consolidation of multi language, multi site publishing system
- · 2000% increase in performance.

#### I.T. Director at The Wharton School

June 2007 - August 2008 (1 year 2 months)

Hired to manage team to redesign and modernize WRDS web site/application for access to warehouse of financial data used by over 200 peer institution clients, providing revenue of about \$9 million a year. (WRDS is a multi terabyte warehouse of financial, accounting, banking, economics, management, and marketing data from multiple international markets accessible through a web-based interface.)

## Responsibilities included:

- · Converting existing site to web standards code base
- · Unifying search for over 200,000 academic texts
- · Creating a community driven site for the users of WRDS
- · Managing a staff to facilitate those goals.

## **Various Positions at The Wharton School**

June 1999 - June 2007 (8 years)

I worked in several roles throughout Wharton, starting as an entry level help desk staffer in 1999, and ending as a manager for a group of three responsible for all web applications at the school by 2007. I worked to support a full service Print shop responsible for all printing needs of the school. I oversaw the IT details of the creation of a remote campus in San Francisco, followed by the construction of a new flagship state-of-the-art facility at the home campus. I supported a staff of 30 lawyers/professors. In short I had a wide range of experiences in my first 8 years at Wharton.

## Writer

2005 - 2006 (1 year)

Content miller, specializing in creating blog posts about the entertainment industry.

# Education

# The University of Pennsylvania

BA, Psychology, September 1995 - May 1999

Activities and Societies: Kappa Alpha Society

# **Terrence Ryan**

Developer Advocate for Google Cloud Platform



Contact Terrence on LinkedIn